RAMESH ADHIKARI

Augusta, Georgia, USA | radhikari@augusta.edu

Website: ramesh-adhikari.github.io | GitHub:ramesh-adhikari | LinkedIn: adramesh

PERSONAL PROFILE

A Ph.D. student at School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University. My research interests areas are in Distributed Algorithms, Blockchain Technology, and Computer Vision. I have 3.5 years of working experience in the field of information technology and services industry as a Software Engineer.

EDUCATION

School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University

Ph.D. in Computer and Cyber Sciences

Pokhara University

Masters of Science in Computer Engineering

Tribhuvan University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Augusta, Georgia, USA Aug 2022 - Present

Kathmandu, Nepal

2018 - 2021

Kathmandu Nana

Kathmandu, Nepal

2013 - 2017

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Ramesh Adhikari, and Costas Busch. Lockless Blockchain Sharding with Multiversion Control, SIROCCO 2023 (2023)

Ramesh Adhikari, and Suresh Pokharel. Performance Evaluation of Convolutional Neural Network Using Synthetic Medical Data Augmentation Generated by GAN. International Journal of Image and Graphics (2021): 2350002

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant | Augusta University | Augusta, Georgia, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

Working on the distributed algorithm and blockchain technology, mainly on sharding in blockchain to solve the scalability issue, under the supervision of Dr. Costas Busch.

Graduate Student | Nepal College of Information Technology | Kathmandu, Nepal

2020 - 2021

Worked on machine learning and deep learning under faculty members' to complete master's research.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Sanima Bank | Kathmandu, Nepal

May 2019 - Jun 2022

- Developed web applications for the banking process.
- Integrated API and web services.
- Developed Batch Script and SQL query to automate the process.

Software Engineer | SmartMobe Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Kathmandu, Nepal

Feb 2018 - April 2019

- Developed the API for mobile and web applications in collaboration with a team of 30 people by using relatable best practices and the latest technology and trends while keeping in mind the quality of code, scalability, and security.
- Researched new tools and technologies and made necessary changes or suggestions after weighing all alternatives. Continuously improve efficiency using new technologies and automation.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND PARTICIPATION

- Travel award, \$1000 from Graduate School, Augusta University, to present the paper in SIROCCO 2023 conference in Madrid, Spain, Mar 2023
- Presented poster at 3rd annual workshop on Emerging Data Science Methods for Complex Biomedical and Cyber Data at Augusta University, Mar 2023
- NSF travel award for the 3rd data science workshop at Augusta University, Feb 2023
- Attended International Symposium on Distributed Computing (DISC) conference, 2022, awarded by Augusta University, 2022.
- Star Performance Excellence Award, Sanima Bank Ltd, 2021.
- Full Scholarship for Master of Science in Computer Engineering from Pokhara University, 2018.
- Worked as a member of Kathford FOSS Community in Kathford Int'l college, monitored and guided the participants in EVOLVE() 2.0 software competition, 2017.
- First Runner Up, Software competition at Kantipur engineering college, 2015.

SKILLS

Programming languages, Libraries, Tools: Python | Go | C | C++ | JavaScript | PHP | Tensorflow | MySQL | SQL server | Shell Scripting

Broad Skills: Distributed Algorithm | Distributed System | Blockchains | Algorithmic Analysis | Web Scraping | Database Design | Machine Learning | Cloud Computing | Problem Solving

SELECTED PROJECTS

- Sharding in Blockchain [work in progress]
- Lockless transaction in Blockchain Sharding using multi-version concurrency control [work in progress]
- Implemented Blockchain Technology in the E-voting system
- Enhanced the performance of Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) by synthetically generating medical data using a generative adversarial network (GAN). [master's thesis]
- Designed microservice architecture and developed a workflow management system for Banking Industry.